export const GENERALKNOWLEDGEINARTSA2019 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The period of perfection in the history of art is",
A: "Hellenistic",
B: "Reformation.",
C: "impressionism.",
D: "Renaissance.",
answer: "D. Renaissance",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Formal balance is also called",
A: "symmetry",
B: "equilibrium.",
C: "equidistant.",
D: "asymmetry",
answer: "A. symmetry",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Saturation of colour is its",
A: "brilliance",
B: "purity",
C: "shade.",
D: "tint.",
answer: "B. purity",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Palaeolithic art is also called",
A: "animal art.",
B: "cult art.",
C: "marble art.",
D: "temple art.",
answer: "A. animal art",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Dynamic movement is depicted by the use of curves and",
A: "diagonal lines.",
B: "straight lines.",
C: "horizontal lines.",
D: "vertical lines.",
answer: "A. diagonal lines",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The visual tension created in a painting is called",
A: "dominance.",
B: "rhythm.",
C: "opposition.",
D: "stability",
answer: "C. opposition",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Problem solving in art begins with",
A: "definition.",
B: "identification.",
C: "investigation.",
D: "solution.",
answer: "B. identification",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Linear perspective was discovered during the.",
A: "Baroque period",
B: "Hellenistic period",
C: "Byzantine period",
D: "Renaissance period",
answer: "D. Renaissance period",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Colours next to each other on the colour wheel are known as",
A: "analogous.",
B: "complementary.",
C: "contrasting.",
D: "triads.",
answer: "A. analogous",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The relationship of parts of a drawing to the whole is termed",
A: "balance.",
B: "rhythm.",
C: "proportion.",
D: "variety.",
answer: "C. proportion",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Ancient Greeks painted on",
A: "temples.",
B: "tombs.",
C: "vases.",
D: "walls.",
answer: "C. vases",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Which of the following is a quality of a creative person?",
A: "Friendliness",
B: "Quietness",
C: "Curiosity",
D: "Worrisomeness",
answer: "C. Curiosity",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Nok sculptures were mainly of",
A: "bronze.",
B: "ivory.",
C: "clay.",
D: "wood",
answer: "C. clay",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Sympathetic magic was effective because it",
A: "charmed wild animals.",
B: "attracted animal to hunters.",
C: "destroyed the eyes of animals.",
D: "inspired bravery in the caveman.",
answer: "D. inspired bravery in the caveman",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Which of these is a physical property of colour?",
A: "Intensity",
B: "Plane",
C: "Prism",
D: "Space",
answer: "A. Intensity",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Emotions of calmness and repose are evoked by using",
A: "diagonal lines.",
B: "spiral lines.",
C: "horizontal lines.",
D: "vertical lines.",
answer: "C. horizontal lines",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The ancient Egyptians portrayed the shoulders of their figures in full view because ,",
A: "artists were unskilled",
B: "artists followed a tradition.",
C: "drawing the shoulder was their specialty.",
D: "details of the chest were easy to depict.",
answer: "B. artists followed a tradition",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Emphasis on the human figure was dominant in the",
A: "Archaic period",
B: "Hellenistic period",
C: "Classical period",
D: "Geometric period",
answer: "C. Classical period",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Chiwara headdress is used for",
A: "agricultural purposes.",
B: "everyday activities.",
C: "ancestral purposes.",
D: "initiation rites.",
answer: "A. agricultural purposes",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of these artists is a three-dimensional designer?",
A: "Book illustrator",
B: "Poster designer",
C: "Package designer",
D: "Sign writer",
answer: "C. Package designer",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Recording the beliefs and practices of people is mainly done through",
A: "belief in animism.",
B: "ecological findings.",
C: "cultural beliefs.",
D: "works of art.",
answer: "D. works of art",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The men’s secret society for the Mende ethnic group is",
A: "Bundu.",
B: "Flankuru.",
C: "Komo.",
D: "Poro",
answer: "D. Poro",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Which of the following countries is associated with the mastaba?",
A: "Austria",
B: "China",
C: "Egypt",
D: "India",
answer: "C. Egypt",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Colours which cannot be produced by , a mixture of pigments are",
A: "complementary colours.",
B: "secondary colours.",
C: "primary colours.",
D: "triad colours.",
answer: "C. primary colours",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Identify the factors which are associated with the alphabets.",
A: "Breadth, texture and style",
B: "Stroke, space and weight",
C: "Height, line and form",
D: "Weight, width and character.",
answer: "B. Stroke, space and weight",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. To depict tonal gradation in shading, the artist considers",
A: "light, medium and dark tones.",
B: "highlight, middle tone and tone.",
C: "reflected light, shadow and soft tones.",
D: "highlight, halftone and shadows.",
answer: "A. light, medium and dark tones",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. A picture or pattern produced by arranging together variously coloured small pieces of glass, stone and tile is",
A: "collage.",
B: "montage.",
C: "Mosaic",
D: "mural.",
answer: "C. Mosaic",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which branch of art is valued for its usefulness rather than its beauty?",
A: "Applied",
B: "Body",
C: "Fine",
D: "Verbal",
answer: "A. Applied",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The arrangements of elements and principles for a particular effect is known as",
A: "applied art.",
B: "perspective.",
C: "composition.",
D: "still life.",
answer: "C. composition",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The process of manipulating plastic material into desired form is called",
A: "casting.",
B: "modelling.",
C: "jiggering.",
D: "throwing.",
answer: "B. modelling",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Verbal arts include",
A: "dancing and prayers.",
B: "prayers and incantations.",
C: "drumming and poetry.",
D: "scarification and incantations.",
answer: "B. prayers and incantations",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Spreading ink or dye through a mesh for printing is facilitated by the use of a",
A: "foam.",
B: "roller.",
C: "squeegee.",
D: "tjanting.",
answer: "C. squeegee",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The ametikpakpe of the Ewe tribe is used for",
A: "ancestral worship.",
B: "puberty rites.",
C: "naming ceremony.",
D: "twin worship.",
answer: "D. twin worship",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Passing a beam of light through a glass prism produces",
A: "achromatic colours.",
B: "secondary colours.",
C: "chiaroscuro.",
D: "the spectrum.",
answer: "D. the spectrum",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The shango staff is associated with the",
A: "Bambara of Mali.",
B: "Mende of Sierra Leone.",
C: "Baule of Cote d’Ivoire.",
D: "Yoruba of Nigeria",
answer: "D. Yoruba of Nigeria",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. A head in profile means that it is drawn in",
A: "frontal view.",
B: "side view.",
C: "full view.",
D: "three quarter view",
answer: "B. side view",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. A paper pulp mixed with glue is suitable for",
A: "Carving",
B: "skiving.",
C: "modelling.",
D: "throwing.",
answer: "C. modelling",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The painting, Mona Lisa was executed by",
A: "Leonardo da Vinci.",
B: "Pablo Picasso.",
C: "Michelangelo Buonarroti.",
D: "Vincent Van Gogh.",
answer: "A. Leonardo da Vinci",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The contrast between light and dark tones in a picture is known as",
A: "balance.",
B: "proportion.",
C: "dominance.",
D: "value.",
answer: "D. value",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Identify the colour that adds to violet and orange to form a triad",
A: "Black",
B: "Red orange",
C: "Green",
D: "Yellow-orange",
answer: "C. Green",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]